Higher. Further. Faster.
Captain Marvel is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Ryan Fleck.
The story follows Carol Danvers as she becomes one of the universe’s most powerful heroes
when Earth is caught in the middle of a galactic war between two alien races.
Set in the 1990s, Captain Marvel is an all-new adventure from a previously
unseen period in the history of the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
Carol Danvers / Vers / Captain Marvel, played by Brie Larson.
Nick Fury, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Talos / Keller, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Yon-Rogg, played by Jude Law.
Supreme Intelligence / Dr. Wendy Lawson, played by Annette Bening.
Korath, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Captain Marvel is a 2019 American superhero film based on Marvel Comics
featuring the character Carol Danvers / Captain Marvel.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures, it is the 21st film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Anna Boden and Ryan Fleck from a
screenplay they co-wrote with Geneva Robertson-Dworet.
It stars Brie Larson as Carol Danvers, alongside Samuel L.
Jackson, Ben Mendelsohn, Djimon Hounsou, Lee Pace, Lashana Lynch,
Gemma Chan, Annette Bening, Clark Gregg, and Jude Law.
Set in 1995, the story follows Danvers as she becomes Captain
Marvel after Earth is caught in a galactic conflict.
Development began by May 2013.
The film was officially announced in October 2014 as
Marvel Studios' first female-led project.
Nicole Perlman and Meg LeFauve were hired to write it the following April after submitting separate takes on the
character, and borrowed elements from Roy Thomas's 1971 "Kree–Skrull War" comic book storyline.
Larson was announced as Danvers at the 2016 San Diego Comic-Con,
with Boden and Fleck hired to direct in April 2017.
Robertson-Dworet was soon hired to re-write the script, and the
rest of the cast were added by the start of filming.
Location shooting began in January 2018, with principal photography starting
that March in California and concluding in Louisiana in July 2018.
Several actors reprise their roles from previous MCU
films, including Jackson and Gregg.
They were both digitally de-aged in post-production
to reflect the film's 1990s setting.
Captain Marvel premiered in London on February 27, 2019, and was theatrically
released in the United States on March 8 as part of Phase Three of the MCU.
The film grossed over $1.1 billion worldwide, making it the first
female-led superhero film to pass the billion-dollar mark.
It became the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2019 and was the
23rd-highest-grossing film of all time during its theatrical run.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, with
praise for the performances—particularly Larson's.
Audience responses were also positive, although the audience reception
section on Rotten Tomatoes was subject to review bombing.
A sequel, The Marvels, was released on November 10, 2023.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
alien invasion, super power, female hero.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.